Guide to the Allan R. Holmberg collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966.
Holmberg, Allan R., collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966
- Series I. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 1)
  - Reprints, Publications and Papers
    - Cornell Peru Project Scientific Reports
      - 44. Chadbourn, Cheryl. Concepts of Disease in a Peruvian Indian Community. N.Y.: Cornell University. 1962. (mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - 46. Collazos Chiriboga, Carlos. La Familia Peruana, Suma y Resta de su Nutricion. Lima. 1954. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 47. Collazos Chiriboga, Carlos; et al. "Dietary Surveys in Peru, III. Chacan and Vicos. Rural Communities in the Peruvian Andes," Journal of the American Dietetic Association, 30 (Dec.) 1222-1230. 1954. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - 49. Collier, John and Mary. "An Experiment in Applied Anthropology," Scientific American, 196:l (Jan.) 37-45. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 51. Dobyns, Henry F. "Migracion e Integracion," pp. 18-20 in No. 60. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - 52. Dobyns, Henry F. a. Basic Problems of Development in the Callejon de Huaylas. b. Problemas Basicos en el Desarrollo del Callejon de Huaylas. Lima: Cornell Peru Project. 1961. (mimeograph) (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 54. Dobyns, Henry F. "Estructura del Buro de Asuntos Indigenas de los EE. UU.," Peru Indigena, IX:20 y 21 (Enero-Junio) 145-150. 1961. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 55. Dobyns, Henry F. Social Solutions for Real and Perceived Aridity in the Andes, N.Y.: Cornell University. 1963. (mimeograph) (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - 56. Dobyns, Henry F. "An Outline of Andean Epidemic History to 1720," Bulletin of the History of Medicine, 37:6 (Nov.-Dec.) 493-515. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 57. Dobyns, Henry F.; Monge M., Carlos; and Vazquez, Mario C. a. "Desarrollo Comunal y Regional," Peru Indigena, IX:20-21 (Enero-Junio) 133-139. 1961. b. "Summary of Technical-Organizational Progress and Reactions To It," Human Organization, 21:2 (Summer) 109-115. 1962. c. "A Contagious Experiment, The Vicos Idea Has Spread Throughout Peru," Saturday Review, Nov. 3, pp. 59-62. 1962. e. 1962 H. O. abstracted in Ekistics (Athens) 14:85 (Dec.) 285-286. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 58. Dobyns, Henry F.; and Carrasco R., Ella. Un Analisis de la Situacion de las Comunidades Indigenas en el Ambiente Nacional. Lima: Cornell Peru Project Pamphlets No. 1. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 59. Dobyns, Henry F.; and Carrasco R., Ella. The Indigenous Communities of Pasco. Preliminary Report. Lima: Cornell Peru Project (mimeograph). 1962. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 60. Dobyns, Henry F.; and Vazquez. Mario C. Migracion e Integracion en el Peru. Lima: Editorial Estudios Andinos Monografia Andina No. 2. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - 61. Doughty, Paul L. Some Indices of Revolution in Latin America. Ithaca: Cornell Peru Project (mimeograph). 1960. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - 62. Doughty, Paul L. El Caso de Huaylas: Un Distrito en la Perspectiva Nacional. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). also in No. 60. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - 63. Doughty, Paul L. Community Organization and Culture Change in Huaylas Peru. Ithaca: Cornell Peru Project (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - 66. Doughty, Paul L. The Peace Corps Volunteer as an Agent of Change in the Peruvian Sierra. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1963. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 67. Doughty, Paul L.; and Andrews, David H. a. Rural Peruvian Views of President J. F. Kennedy. Lima: Cornell Peru Project (mimeograph). 1961. b. Presentaciones de Representantes de Varias Comunidades del Callejon de Huaylas Visitadas por el Senor Edward K. Kennedy. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - 68. Fearer, Jane. An Analysis of Vicos Schoolboy Perception of Their Kinship System: An Experiment in using a projective typing test technique. Cambridge: Radcliffe College (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - 69. Fine, Norman L. Coca Chewing: A Social Versus a Nutritional Interpretation. N.Y.: Columbia University (mimeograph). 1960. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - 71. Fried, Jacob. a. "Enfermedad y Organizacion Social," Etnologia y Arqueologia, Lima: Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos I:l 38-49. 1960. b. The Social Organization and Value System of a Peruvian Hacienda Community: Vicos. Ithaca: Cornell University. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - 77. Ghersi Barrera, Humberto. Caracteristicas de la Migracion en el Distrito de Marcara. Museo de la Cultura Peruana. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1961. also in No. 60, 1963. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - 78. Ghersi Barrera, Humberto; and Dobyns, Henry F. Migracion por Etapas: El Caso del Valle de Viru. Museo de la Cultura Peruana. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeographed). 1961. also in No. 60, 1963. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - 79. Goldsen, Rose K.; and Stein, William W. The Introduction of NSP in Vicos: The Story Line. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Sociology and Anthropology (mimeograph) 1956. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - 80. Hickman, Carolyn C. Early Child Care Among the Chinchera Aymara. Ithaca: Cornell University (duplicated). 1962. (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - 83. Hickman, John V. Peruvian Aymara and Their Dialectic of Progress. Ithaca: Cornell University (duplicated). 1962. (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - 86. Holmberg, Allan R. "Child Training in Vicos, Peru," Delphian Quarterly, No. 34 (Jan.) 3-8. 1951. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - 87. Holmberg, Allan R. Excerpt from The Interrelations of Demographic, Economic, and Social Problems in Selected Underdeveloped Areas. N.Y.: Milbank Memorial Fund, pp. 143-149. 1954. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - 88. Holmberg, Allan R. a. Experimental Intervention in a Field Situation. paper delivered at the 1955 Annual Meeting of the Society for Applied Anthropology, Bloomington, Indiana. b. "Participant Intervention in the Field," Human Organization. 14:l 23-26. (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - 90. Holmberg, Allan R. "The Research and Development Approach to the Study of Change," Human Organization, 17:l (Spring) 12-16. 1958. (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - 91. Holmberg, Allan R. "Land Tenure and Planned Social Change: A Case from Vicos, Peru," Human Organization, 18:l (Spring) 7-10. 1959. (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - 92. Holmberg, Allan R. "Participant Intervention in the Field," Human Organization, 14:l (Spring) 23-26. 1955. (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - 94. Holmberg, Allan R. "Age in the Andes," p. 86-90 in Robert J. Smith (ed.) "Cultural Differences in the Life Cycle and the Concept of Time," 1961. (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - 96. Holmberg, Allan R. and Dobyns, Henry F. "The Process of Accelerating Community Change," Human Organization, 21:2 (Summer) 107-109. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - 97. Holmberg, Allan R. and Dobyns, Henry F. Integrated Community Development-The Vicos Experience. Ithaca: Cornell Department of Anthropology. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - 98. Holmberg, Allan R.; Dobyns, Henry F.; and Vazquez, Mario C. "Methods for the-Analysis-of Cultural Change," Anthropological Quarterly, 34:2 (April) 27-46. 1961. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - 99. Huenemann. Ruth L. "Nutrition and Care of Young Children in Peru," Journal of the American Dietetic Association, 30:6 (June) 554-558. 1954. (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - 102. Kauffmnn Doig, Federico. "Las ruinas de Chopijirca (Vicos, Ancash)," Revista del Museo Nacional, XXV, pp. 120-139. 1956. (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - 103. Kennedy, John L.; and Lasswell, Harold D. "A Cross-Cultural Test of Self-Image," Human Organization, 17:l (Spring) 41-43. 1958. (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - 104. Lasswell, Harold D. "Integrating Communities into More Inclusive Systems," Ekistics, (Athens) 14:85 (Dec.) 286-289. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - 107. Mangin, William P. "Estratificacion social en el Callejon de Huaylas." Revista del Museo Nacional, XXIV, pp. 174-189. 1955. (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - 108. Mangin, William P. "Haciendas, Comunidades and Strategic Acculturation in the Peruvian Sierra," Sociologus, 7:2, pp. 142-146. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - 109. Mangin, William P. "La bebida entre los indios de los Andes," Peru Indigena, VII:16-17 (Julio-Dic.) 14-22. 1958. (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - 110. Mangin, William P. "Organization Social en Vicos," Etnologia y Arqueologia, (Institute de Etnologia, Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos) 1:l. pp. 24-37. 1960. (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - 111. Mangin, William P. "Fiestas in an Indian Community in Peru," pp. 84-92 in Symposium: Patterns of Land Utilization and Other Papers. 1961. (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - 114. Monge Medrano, Carlos. "La Distribucion Vertical de la Vida en el Peru: Migraciones y Nomadismo," pp. 11-17 in No. 60. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - 115. Monge Medrano, Carlos. "Clausura del Simposio," p. 187 in No. 60. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - 116. Monge Medrano, Carlos; and Vazquez, Mario C. "Antropologia y Medicina," Peru Indigena, VII:14-15 (Julio) 19-33. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - 117. Monge Medrano, Carlos; and Vazquez, Mario C. "El Proceso de Aculturacion de Vicos," Peru Indigena, X:22 y 23, pp. 9-15. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - 118. Montalvo Vidal, Abner. Salud Publica y Una Pelicula en Vicos. Lima: Talleres Educacion Sanitaria, Ministerio de Salud Publica y Asistencia Social. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - 120. Montoya Rojas, Rodrigo. "Eleccion de Dirigentes: Aceptacion y Resistencia, " Cuadernos, II:l (Julio) 60-82. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - 121. Newman, Marshall T.; and Collazos Chiriboga, Carlos. "Growth and skeletal maturation in malnourished Indian boys from the Peruvian Sierra," American Journal of Physical Anthropology, 15:3 (Sept.) 431. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - 123. Patch, Richard W. An Hacienda Becomes a Community. American Universities Field Staff Newsletter, Oct. 4, 1957. (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - 125. Payne, E. H.; Gonzales-Mugaburu, L.; and Schliecher, E. M. "An Intestinal Parasite Survey in the High Cordilleras of Peru. I," American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 5:4 (July) 696-698. 1956. (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - 126. Price, Richard. Watanaki: Courtship and Marriage Institutions in Vicos, Peru. Cambridge: Harvard University, (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 9, Folder 54)
      - 127. Proyecto Peru-Cornell. Presentaciones de Representantes de Varias Comunidades del Callejon de Huaylas Visitadas por el Senor Edward K. Kennedy. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1961 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      - 128. Richards de Dobyns, Cara E. Urban Peruvian Medical Concepts. paper read before the American Anthropological Association 1961 Annual Meeting, Philadelphia. Lima: Cornell Peru Project (mimeograph) (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - 130. Snyder, Joan C. "The Changing Context of an Andean Community," Cultural Stability and Cultural Change, American Ethnological Society Annual Spring Meeting, pp. 20-29. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - 132b. Stein, William W. Recommendations for a Modernization Program in Peru. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology, (mimeograph). 1950 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      - 133. Stein, William W. "The Case of the Hungry Calves," Human Organization, 15:l (Spring) 15-21. 1956. (Box 9, Folder 59)
      - 134. Stein, William W. "Outside Contact and Cultural Stability in a Peruvian Highland Village," Cultural Stability and Cultural Change, (Spring) pp. 15-19. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - 136. Stevens, Robert D. Agricultural Production on Hacienda Vicos, Description and Analysis of a Hacienda Agricultural Society in the Andes of Peru. Ithaca: Department of Sociology & Anthropology (mimeograph). 1954. (Box 9, Folder 61)
        [See also Separated Materials]
      - 137b. Stycos, J. Mayone. Considerations in the Analysis of Population Characteristics. (copy). (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - 138. Stycos, J. Mayone. Culture and Differential Fertility in Peru. paper presented at Inter-American Meeting of Sociologists. Princeton. Ithaca: Department of Sociology (mimeograph). 1962. (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - 139. Stycos, J. Mayone; and Richards de Dobyns, Cara. Fuentes de la migracion a la Gran Lima. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1961. also in No. 60. pp. 37-44. (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - 142. Trigoso P., Jorge. "Instrumentos Musicales de Vicos," Cuadernos, II:l (Julio) 53-59. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - 143. Tuohy, William S. A Study of the Political and Administrative Position of Vicos a Peruvian Indian Community. N.Y.: Columbia-Cornell-Harvard Summer Field Studies Program (mimeograph). 1962. (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - 148. Vazquez, Mario C. The Peruvian Elite. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Sociology & Anthropology (mimeograph). 1959. (Box 9, Folder 67)
      - 150. Vazquez, Mario C. Proceso de Migracion en la Comunidad de Vicos, Ancash. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1961. also in No. 60 pp. 93-102. (Box 9, Folder 68)
      - 151. Vazquez, Mario C. Hacienda, Peonaje y Servidumbre en los Andes Peruanos. Lima: Editorial Estudios Andinos, Monografias Andinas No. 1. 1961. (Box 9, Folder 69)
      - 152. Vazquez, Mario C. Educacion Formal en una Comunidad Rural Indigena: "Vicos." Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell, (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - 154. Vazquez, Mario C. "Cambios Socio-Economicos en una Hacienda Andina del Peru," America Indigena, XXII:4 (Oct.) 297-312. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - 155. Vazquez, Mario C.; and Dobyns, Henry F. a. Transformacion de las Haciendas con Peonaje y Servidumbre en Cooperativas de Produccion. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1963. b. The Transformation of Manors into Producers' Cooperatives. Ithaca: Comparative Studies of Cultural Change, Cornell Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1964. (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - 156. Whyte, William F.; and Holmberg, Allan R. a. Human Problems of U.S. Enterprise in Latin America. Special number, Human Organization, 15:3 (Autumn). 1956. b. "From Paternalism to Democracy," Community Development Bulletin, IX:l (Dec.) 13-19. 1957. c. "Some Fundamental Assumptions of Latin American Culture," Case Studies in Foreign Operation, pp. 207-221. 1957. d. "Problems of U.S. Enterprise in Latin America," review of 156a. in Looking Ahead, National Planning Association, 5:6 (Sept.) 4. 1957. (Box 9, Folder 73)
      - II.6. Alers, J. Oscar. Population and Development in a Peruvian Community. Ithaca: Cornell University Comparative Studies of Cultural Change (mimeograph). 1964. also in Journal of Inter-American Studies, VI1:4 (Oct.) 423-448. 1965. (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - II.7. Andrews, David H.; et al. Paucartambo, Pasco, Peru, Whence...Whither. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities, Report No. 7, Cornell University. 1965. also correspondence between Andrews and Dobyns, and a list of errata. (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - II.9. Bornstein, George J. Holy Places and Their Effect on Conduct in Vicos, Ancash, Peru. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - II.10. Castillo, Hernan; Castillo, Teresa; and Revilla, Arcenio. Accopata: The Reluctant Recipient of Technological Change. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities. Re-p ort No. 2 Cornell University. 1963. (Box 9, Folder 77)
      - II.11. Castillo, Hernan; Castillo, Teresa; and Revilla, Arcenio. Carcas: La Comunidad Olvidada. Lima: Editorial Estudios Andinos. 1965. (Box 9, Folder 78)
      - II.12. Castillo, Hernan; Castillo, Teresa; and Revilla, Arcenio. Carcas: The Forgotten Community. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities. Report No. 1. Cornell University. (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - II.13. Castillo, Hernan; et al. Chaquicocha: Community in Progress. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities. Report No. 5. Cornell University. 1964. (Box 9, Folder 80)
      - II.14. Castillo, Hernan; et al. Mito: The Orphan of Its Illustrious Children. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities, Report No. 4. Cornell University. 1964. (Box 9, Folder 81)
      - II.15. Dobyns, Henry F. Las Comunidades Indigena Peruanas en el Desarrollo Nacional. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 9, Folder 82)
      - II.16. Dobyns, Henry F. Change Without Design in the Central Andes. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1966. (Box 9, Folder 83)
      - II.17. Dobyns, Henry F. Peasants, Politics, and Peace in the Andes. Salt Lake City Address. (mimeograph) (Box 9, Folder 84)
      - II.18. Dobyns, Henry F. "Problemas sociales del desarrollo agrario Peruano," Mensajero Agricola, XXIII: 148 (marzo) 8-12. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 85)
      - II.19. Dobyns, Henry F. The Social Matrix of Peruvian Indigenous Communities. Ithaca: Cornell Peru Project Monograph. 1964. (Box 9, Folder 86)
      - II.20. Dobyns, Henry F.; Doughty, Paul L.; and Holmberg, Allan R. Measurement of Peace Corps Program Impact in the Peruvian Andes. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - II.21. Doughty, Paul L. "La Migration Provinciana, Regionalismo, y el Desarrollo Local," Revista de Economia y Agricultura, May, pp. 203-211. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - II.22. Doughty, Paul L.; and Negron, Luis. Pararin: A Break with the Past. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities, Report No. 6. Cornell University. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - II.23. Ducker, Paul. A Study of Ethnocentrism in Vicos Peru. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1964. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - II.24. Holmberg, Allan R. Some Relationships between Psychobiological Deprivation and Culture Change in the Andes. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1966. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - II.25. Holmberg, Allan R.; et al. "The Vicos Case: Peasant Society in Transition," The American Behavioral Scientist, VIII:7 (March) 1965. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - II.26. Kelly, Patricia May. Legends of the Saints of Vicos. Ithaca: Cornell University (mimeograph). 1962. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - II.27. Korb, George M. Ticaco, An Aymara Indian Community. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities, Report No. 8. Cornell University. 1966. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - II.28. Lanning, Edward P. "Highland South America," American Antiquity, 31:1, p. 140. 1965. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - II.29. Maynard, Eileen A. Patterns of Community Service Development in Selected Communities of the Mantaro Valley, Peru. Ithaca: Socio-Economic Development of Andean Communities, Report No. 3. Cornell University. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - II.30. Maynard, Eileen A. The Peace Corps in Peru: A Final Report on Volunteer Performance, Problems and Attitudes. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - II.31. Montalva Vidal, Abner. El Compadrazgo o parentino espiritual en una colectividad de colonies de hacienda en la Sierra Central del Peru. Lima: Universidad Nacional de San Marcos, Tesis de Bachiller. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - II.32. Richardson, Gail. School Drop-Outs in Viru. Ithaca: Cornell University (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 10)
      - II.33. Skalka, Harold. Some Aspects of Vicos Mythology and Folklore. Ithaca: Cornell University (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - II.34. Stein, William W. Changing Vicos Agriculture. Buffalo: Council on International Studies, SUNY at Buffalo. 1972. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - II.35. Vazquez, Mario C. Educacion rural en el Callejon de Huaylas: Vicos. Lima: Editorial Estudios Andinos. 1965. (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - II.36. Vazquez, Mario C. Inmigracion y Mestizaje en el Peru. Ithaca: Cornell Latin American Year (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Popular Descriptions of the Cornell Peru Project
      - 157. Anonimo. "Proyecto Peru-Cornell: Vicos constituye el primer Paso firme y seguro do una Pacifica revolucion agraria," Metropoli, I:3 (Feb.) 14-17. 1957. (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - 158. Anonimo. "Credito Agricola Supervisado en Vicos," Peru Integral, No. 2 (Mayo) 4. 1958. (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - 162. Collier, John. "The Tribe That Slept 400 Years," Pageant, 13:6 (Dec.) 40-47. 1957. (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - 163. Curtis, C. Michael. "New Day in Peru," Cornell Alumni News, 64:l0 (May) 1, 6-21. 1962. (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - 165. Doughty, Paul L. "The 'Earth Apple'," National Horticultural Magazine, 38:l (Jan.) 21-25. 1959. (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - 168. Harbord, J. H. The Vicos Experiment. Lima: Cornell Peru Project (pamphlet). 1961. (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - 171. Lear, John. "Reaching the Heart of South America," Saturday Review, Nov. 3, pp. 55-58. 1962. (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - 174. Montalvo Vidal, Abner. "Vicos: Experimento Antropologico," Fanal, XIII:51 pp. 2-7. 1957. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - 175. Newman, Marshall T. "Man and the Heights," Natural History, LXVII:l (Jan.) 9-19. 1958. (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - 176. O'Hara, Hazel. "Science and the Indian," Natural History, LXVII:6 pp. 268-275, 282-283. 1958. (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - 177. (Ravines, Eudocio). "La Demoledora Experiencia de Vicos," Vanguardia, (Lima) No. 203 (13 Nov.) 8-9. 1962. (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - 178. Stowe, Leland. "Miracle at Vicos," Reader's Digest, (April) 222-226, 228. 1963. (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - 179. Talavera T., Juis Gmo. Educacion Civica. Lima: Editorial Colegio Militar Leoncio Prado. (Leccion 17: El Problema del Indio. pp. 88-98.) 1961. (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - 180. Zileri Gibson, Enrique. "Los Quieren Traicionar," Caretas, (1-15 Julio) pp. 12-14. 1961. (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - III.37. Bolton, Ralph. The History of the Founding of a Community in the Andes and the development of its arts and crafts. Peace Corps (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - III.38. Doughty, Paul L. Pitfalls and Progress in the Peruvian Sierra. reprint from Cultural Frontiers of the Peace Corps, ed. by Robert B. Textor. Mass.: M.I.T. Press, pp. 221-241. 1965. (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - III.39. Patch, Richard W. "Vicos and the Peace Corps, a Failure in Intercultural Communication," West Coast South America Series, XI:2 (March) 255-262. 1964. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - III.40. Schechter, Mal. Raised Out of Serfdom in Peru, Indians Show Anxiety Symptoms," Modern Medicine, (Minneapolis), May 10, 1965. also memos to Henry Dobyns. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Cornell Comparative Studies of Cultural Change Scientific Reports
      - IV.41. Alers, J. Oscar. Method and Reliability in the 1963 Survey of Vicos. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - IV.42. Aranguri L., Marcial. Teoria de migracion y migracion en la ciudad de Trujillo, 1940-1956. (mimeograph). 1961. (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - IV.43. Bourne, James Russel and Bourne, Dorothy Dulles. Thirty Years of Change in Ten Selected Areas of Rural Puerto Rico. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1964., 1 volume (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - IV.44. Brown, Jack; and Burela, Alberto; with Dobyns, Henry F. Participant Intervention in Providing Domestic Water. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1964. (Box 10, Folder 39)
      - IV.45. Dobyns, Henry F. Estimating Aboriginal American Population. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1964. (Box 10, Folder 40)
      - IV.46. Dobyns, Henry F. Methodological Limits to Cultural Relativism. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1963. (Box 10, Folder 41)
      - IV.47. Dobyns, Henry F. The Struggle for Land in Peru: The Hacienda Vicos Case. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). 1965. (Box 10, Folder 42)